Hi
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Hi.
欢迎大家
Welcome.
我们的直播
So we're going to get started before we're
即将开始
all full in this room just for the live stream.
我是 Alex Komoroske
I'm Alex Komoroske.
Chrome web平台开发组的产品经理
I'm lead product manager on Chrome's web platform team.
Hi
ELISABETH MORANT: And hi.
我是 Elisabeth Morant
My name is Elisabeth Morant and I am the product manager
Chrome 安全团队的产品经理
for Chrome security.
我们今天将要讨论四个话题
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So today, we're going
有新也有旧
to tell you about four forces, some of them old, some of them
我们把它融合在一起
new, that together combine to create
创造出下一代移动互联网
the next generation mobile web.
我们将在此
Now, a lot of times at I/O, we tell you
告诉你们一些新奇的特性
about all kinds of amazing features
它们会在6个月后和大家见面  也许是一年之后
that are going to come six months, maybe a year from now,
但是今天  我们将要揭开某些特性的面纱
but today, we're going to cover only things that are already
并且在Chrome上你们已经可以使用
shipped in Chrome that you can use.
由于时间有限  所以我们只涵盖了
So we don't have that much time, so we'll cover things
一些很高层面的东西
at a pretty high level, but there's
但是仍然有很多高质量的DevByte以及Box Talk
lots of great DevBytes and Box Talks
供大家在IO上参加
here at I/O that go into more depth on all of these.
让我们开始吧
So let's get started.
Elisabeth和我能站在这的原因只有一个
So the reason that Elisabeth and I are here
那就是我们都爱Chrome
is because we love Chrome.
和大家一样  我们爱Chrome
ELISABETH MORANT: And we love Chrome
是因为我们都爱web
because, like many of you, we love the web.
Web的神奇之处在于
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I mean, it's kind of amazing
你可以不通过任何人的允许
that you can connect with any topic or community you want
就可以连接任何一个主题或者是社区
without asking anyone permission,
让一切神奇的事情得以发生
which allows all kinds of wacky stuff to happen.
我个人最喜欢的站点
So my personal favorite is this site
叫做Real Ultimate Power
called Real Ultimate Power.
有人知道它吗
Anybody know what that is?
我看到你了
So there's a few of you out there.
这是一个讽刺类的主题站点
So this is this amazing satire site.
这位老兄有一个关于忍者的页面
This guy has a page about ninjas.
他对忍着超级痴迷并且痛恨海盗
He's super crazy into ninjas and he hates pirates.
当然
ELISABETH MORANT: Oh, of course.
这才是重点
ALEX KOMOROSKE: That's important.
他把网页挂在那
But he just put this site up there.
人们都捧腹大笑
People thought it was hilarious.
纷纷的去分享它
They shared it.
发现并喜欢它
People found it and loved it.
我们团队也非常喜欢这个
My crew team, we actually found it
以至于也摆pose拍了张照片
and loved it so much that we actually posed
上传到这个站点上面
for a picture as ninjas and uploaded it to the site.
ELISABETH MORANT: OK.
你必须给大家看看这张照片
You have to show everyone this photo.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
我也试图那样做了
I'm trying to psych myself up for that,
但是这照片真是有点年头了
but here's the picture that I am extremely
至今也引以为傲
proud of from a number of years ago.
哪一个是你
ELISABETH MORANT: Which one is you?
我也不是太确定
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So I'm actually not entirely sure,
但是看到了古铜色的皮肤
but based on the farmer's tan, I'm
我确定那个就是我
pretty sure that that one's me.
无论如何  我囧了 这次该轮到你囧了
Anyway, I embarrassed myself, you embarrass yourself.
ELISABETH MORANT: OK.
All right.
我想这样才是公平
I guess it's only fair.
当我12岁的时候  极度痴迷于视频游戏
So when I was 12, I was really into video games, especially
尤其是冒险类游戏  所以我上网并制作了
adventure games, so I took to the internet
我的第一个网站
to make my first website.
这也是我第一次接触编程
And clearly, this was my first introduction to programming
网页中间还有一个巨大的空间
and I owned up to it with the giant space in the bottom
我根本不知道怎么把它去掉
that I didn't know how to get rid of.
非常巧妙
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Very subtle.
但是正是这一次
ELISABETH MORANT: But the point is
才真正的把我和那些
that this let me connect with this huge community of people
具有相同热情的人一起联系起来
out there who had the same passions as I did.
是的  大约400多个呢
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Yeah, all 400 of them,
如果计数器没错的话
if I see that counter right.
其实多半都是我自己刷的
ELISABETH MORANT: Half of them were me refreshing the page.
无论如何这只是一些简单的例子
Anyway, so these are just a few weird examples,
但是web确实是一个强大的技术
but the web is a really powerful technology
它开启了一个昌盛的经济时代
that's enabled a number of very thriving businesses to form.
电子商务在2014年的成交额已经超过了1.5万亿
E-commerce alone in 2014 was worth more than $1.5 trillion.
我的天
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Jeez.
数额非常之巨大
ELISABETH MORANT: That's huge.
T级别的万亿
ALEX KOMOROSKE: That's trillion with a T.
是的
ELISABETH MORANT: Yes.
Wow
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wow.
我们分享了一些过去的例子
So the point of this is we've shared some examples
但是不局限于此
from our past, but we're not alone.
事实上   我敢说这个房间里参与直播的每一个人
In fact, I bet that almost everyone in this room
都已经连上了网
and on the live stream has a connection to the web.
我们都是这个奇妙而强大的全球化社区
It's this amazing, vibrant, weird, global community
其中的一员
that we're all a part of.
这太棒了
It's awesome.
ELISABETH MORANT: OK.
今天的主题是下一代移动网络
So the title of the talk is the next generation mobile web, so
那么我们在移动端上面都能做什么呢
what are we doing on mobile?
问的好
ALEX KOMOROSKE: That's a great question.
移动端是一个重大的改变
So mobile was a fundamental shift.
它由桌面端演化而来
It changed the assumptions from desktop.
所以性能就显得格外重要
So performance became incredibly important,
确保设备上能够达到60fps
making sure that you could hit 60 frames per second
在设备使用电池的情况下
on devices that were running battery power.
并且还有其他功能
And there's other capabilities that
让情况变得更加严峻
just became totally critical.
举个例子  推送通知
Push notifications, for example, are
让你和自己设备进行交互
just crucial to how you interact with your mobile device
web不能做到这些
and the web couldn't do it.
事实上  本地应用就非常的
To be honest, native apps really just
适合这种环境
were well suited to this environment.
ELISABETH MORANT: All right.
你的意思是我们都该去开发本地应用
So I guess we should all just make native apps, then?
我可没说
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I'm not saying that.
如今本地应用非常的出色   但是web也一样毫不逊色
Now, native apps are great, but the web is also amazing.
事实上  它所拥有的一些优点
In fact, a number of its strengths
让其在桌面端更加的强大
that made it so strong on desktop are as strong as ever.
有一天我查看了下
So just the other day I looked, and I
在过去的一周里有多少人使用Devtool
checked to see how many people used DevTools in the past week.
相比来说
So as a point of comparison, Android
Android是一个比较成功的平台
is an amazingly successful platform.
我看到公共统计大约有4百万
I've seen public stats somewhere around four million
而开发者大约则是1百万
or so for an estimate for developers.
你猜有多少人使用了Chrome DevTools
So how many people do you think loaded Chrome DevTools
在过去的一周
in the past week?
一周吗
ELISABETH MORANT: A week?
也许有1百万吧
Maybe a million.
揭晓答案
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Turns out the answer
大约有250万的人使用Chrome DevTools
is 25 million people have used Chrome
在过去的一周
DevTools in the last week.
非常的酷因为这不是一个死的数字
That's really cool because that's not a stagnant number.
仍然一直在增长
That's actually growing over time.
所以这些人并不是都在构造
So the point is not all these people
巨大而又复杂的网站
are building huge, complicated websites.
其中的一些人只是在修修补补
Some of them are tinkering.
我们是这个巨大社区中的一份子
But this community that we're all a part of, it's huge, it's
它在不断的变强变大
strong, and it's growing.
所以今天的演讲就是针对这些
So this talk today is for those people
处在这个社区中  并且热爱web的250万人
in this community, those 25 million people who
而说的
love the web.
[APPLAUSE]
一开始
ELISABETH MORANT: So to start, we're
我们谈论了它的范围  以及web的超强力量
going to talk about reach, the superpower of the web.
我们也聊了一些性能方面的问题
ALEX KOMOROSKE: We're also then talk about performance and how
以及因此产生的巨大变革
we made big strides there.
最后
ELISABETH MORANT: And finally, we're
我们将要谈谈  以及
going to talk about engagement, how we're
我们如何帮助你创造出拟真的体验
helping you build immersive experience that
让用户回来
keep users coming back.
这三个话题虽说是分开的
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So the three of these separately, whatever.
但是联系在一起  与全球化社区相结合起来
But together, combined with that global community,
就变得非常的特别了
that's something special.
Web以及它的成功
ELISABETH MORANT: So the web is extremely successful,
不仅是因为它范围之广
largely because of its reach, and we
don't give it enough credit.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I mean, we give it a fair bit of credit.
我们都知道浏览器能运行在每一个设备
We understand that browsers are on every device
以及每一个操作系统上
and every operating system.
没错
ELISABETH MORANT: That's true.
甚至现在汽车上都有浏览器  我们有超过十亿的Chrome用户
Even now cars have browsers and we have over one billion Chrome
这还不算那些
users, and that doesn't even count
其他的浏览器以及通过它浏览Web的人
other browsers and other people browsing the web.
但是我要谈的是关于范围的另外一方面
But what I'm talking about is another aspect
不是浏览器的范围
of reach, that is, not the reach of browsers
而是内容的范围
but the reach of content.
我思考的方式则是把Web想象成一棵
So the way I think about it is the web
拥有很多节点的树
is a series of trees with nodes, right,
每一个网页都是一棵树  而树根
where every website is a tree and the root is
则是像Pinterest.com之类的站点
like Pinterest.com, and then you dig deep,
然后每一个网页就是树的叶子节点
and then you're on a board and that's a leaf.
你从一个URL跳到另一个URL
And then if you jump from URL to URL,
也就是你从一个叶子节点跳到另一个叶子节点
then you're jumping from leaf node to leaf node
如此这般的
and so on and so forth, and that's
这也是为什么能在链接间跳来跳去
why it's so easy jump between link to link.
我真的不明白
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I have literally no idea
你在说什么
what you're talking about.
ELISABETH MORANT: OK.
Fair.
让我给你展示个例子
Let me show you an example.
好的
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Great.
假如我现在跳到了这个演示的笔记本电脑上
ELISABETH MORANT: So if I could jump to the demo laptop?
Great.
我们打开Imagine Dragons乐队最新的单曲视频
So let's start on a video of the latest Imagine Dragons single,
&quot;Shots.&quot;
我想在座的观众里面
So I know that every single one of you in the audience
应该会有些人和我一样喜欢Imagine Dragons
loves Imagine Dragons probably not as much as I do.
这也许是有史以来最棒的乐队
It's basically the best band that's ever existed.
比Beatles好多了
It's better than the Beatles, really.
我要继续演示了
I could go on about it.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wow.
OK.
Sure.
关键在于web  范围  以及树
ELISABETH MORANT: So the point is the web, reach, trees,
right.
所以Youtube在此就是一棵特别的树
So YouTube is a tree and this particular piece
而视频内容则是一个节点
of video content is a node.
我可以把URL分享给你
And so I could just share a URL with you
然后你就能看到这个内容
and then you can watch this piece of content.
同样的  我也能了解更多关于Imagine Dragon的信息
And likewise, I can learn more about Imagine Dragons,
通过YouTube中的导航链接  或许你可以跳到维基百科
navigate through YouTube, maybe jump to Wikipedia.
这样的话  我就是从其中一个节点跳到了
At this point, I've jumped from one node
另外维基百科这棵树的节点上面
to the node of another tree, the Wikipedia tree,
我也可以获得维基百科上面深层次的内容
and I so easily reached a piece of content deep in Wikipedia
只需点击一下链接
just by clicking a link.
从这里我可以阅读一些文章
And so from here, I can read some articles,
来回的跳转  了解Alt-J  再跳回来
jump around, learn about Alt-J, jump back.
我并没有带你浏览完
I'm not going to bring you through the entirety
整个网络
of the web.
那会花相当长的时间
ALEX KOMOROSKE: That would take a long time.
我能跳转到他们的乐队主页
ELISABETH MORANT: And I can jump to their band website.
这种情况下  我就不需要
In this case, I wouldn't necessarily
那些每一个我喜欢乐队的应用了
want an app for every band that I love,
我只需要去他们的网站就行了
but I do want to be able to go to their website
了解一些信息  比如查看什么时候开巡演之类的
and learn about things like when they're going on tour
Alex
and find out-- hey, Alex?
怎么了
ALEX KOMOROSKE: What?
你能等一下吗
ELISABETH MORANT: Can you take over for a second?
他们正在开巡演
I just-- they're on tour and I know
并且票已经快要卖光了
the tickets are going to sell out
我需要现在就买上一张
and I just really need to buy a ticket right now.
你逗我呢吧
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Are you kidding me?
就一会儿
ELISABETH MORANT: Please?
你知道slide的
You know the slides.
好
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
事实上我也可以跳转到WolfVision
ELISABETH MORANT: Actually, can we jump to WolfVision
这样我就能和所有人分享买票的这个经历了
so everyone can share in this experience of buying tickets
with me?
Wow
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wow.
看来你真是Imagine Dragons的铁杆粉
You really love Imagine Dragons.
我爱Imagine Dragons
ELISABETH MORANT: I love Imagine Dragons.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
她正在做的这件事
While she's doing that, it's kind of cool
这真是一件非常酷的事情
what she was doing.
在几十秒钟内
In the course of a few seconds, she
她先后浏览了大约七种不同的服务
visited what, like seven different services,
都没有安装任何的东西
all without installing anything.
非常棒
That's kind of cool.
这一切在web上
It's something that just happens that we totally
就好像理所当然一样
take for granted on the web.
抱歉
ELISABETH MORANT: Anyway, sorry.
我回来了
I'm back.
I'm back, guys.
票现在还没开卖
So it turns out the tickets aren't on sale yet,
所以我到了它们的网站
so I just went to their website and opted
选择了售票时通知我
to get a notification when they come back on sale.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
我们刚才谈到哪里了
ELISABETH MORANT: Anyway, so where were we?
我们能回到之前的那页slide吗?
Can we go back to the slides?
关于范围的
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Something about reach, I think.
ELISABETH MORANT: Oh right.
Friction.
Friction sucks, friction being the amount of overhead
from a user wanting to get somewhere to actually being
able to get to that piece of content, and on the web,
它就像点击链接一样简单
it's as easy as just tapping a link.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
我想我知道这是怎么一回事了
So I think I see what's going on here
但是这似乎太抽象了
but this seems all really abstract.
你能举一个实际的例子吗
Is this something that actually matters in practice?
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah.
例子来了
So here's something.
平均每个用户每个月大约使用12到20个应用
On average, the average person uses around 12 to 20 apps
在他们的手机上
per month on their phone.
取决于你用的哪一个统计数据了
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Depending on which stat you use.
是的取决于你看的哪一个数据源
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah, depending on what source
you look at.
猜一猜Chrome for Android 用户
So keeping that in mind, guess how many sites
平均每月要访问多少个站点
the average Chrome for Android user visits in every month.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
也包括第三方内容以及页面吗
So are we including third party content and iframes and stuff?
不
ELISABETH MORANT: No.
就只是直接的导航链接
I'm talking about direct link navigation,
通过Omnibox
going through the Omnibox.
都是些不同的域名
This is all unique domains.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
使用12到20个应用的话
So 12 to 20 for apps.
那么这个应该是那个的两倍 40个
Maybe double that, like 40 or so.
超过100个网站
ELISABETH MORANT: Over 100 websites a month.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wow.
这真蛮令人震惊
That's actually really impressive.
我从未意识到有这么大
I didn't realize it was going to be that big.
看见了吗
ELISABETH MORANT: See?
这就是web所能触及的范围
That right there is reach in action.
人们可以通过简单的点击
It's so easy for people to just tap a link
就访问数以万计的站点
and visit tons of new sites with no friction.
事实上美国运营商的移动流量
And in fact, it turns out that 85% of US retailers'
占到了Web流量的85%
mobile traffic is on the web, and that accounts
并且占它们收入的90%以上
for 90% of their revenue.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wow.
这仅仅只是一个例子
ELISABETH MORANT: And now this is just one example,
这也是我为什么说Web有着超强的力量
and this is why I consider reach the superpower of the web.
所以我的结论就是
So the way I think of it is-- bear with me-- you want people
如果你想要人们和你的东西产生联系
to form a meaningful relationship with your stuff,
人们必须得能发现它
but first people have to find it.
Web就像一个巨大的速配会
So it's kind of like the web is one big speed dating venue
你可以从一个人跳到另外一个人
where you can jump from person to person and get to know them
一点一点的接触他  就像你从一个站点跳到另一个站点一样
a little bit, just like you can jump from website to website
在你没和那部分内容建立关系之前
and get to know it a little bit before committing
你就能对它有所了解
and developing a relationship with that content.
你无需担心非得点击一个链接
And you're never afraid to necessarily click
因为最坏的情况下又能发生什么呢
a link because what's the worst that can happen?
五分钟后  铃响了
After five minutes, the bell rings and you
你又要移动到了另外一个地方
move onto the next place.
关键在于只要你想
And the point is that then, when you decide you want to commit,
你就能快速的建立联系
you can build that relationship over time.
这前所未有的重要
And so we take reach for granted but it's really
as important as ever.
这就是Web的延伸范围
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So that's reach, but of course,
和移动端的性能一样重要
just as important on mobile is performance.
但是你又如何去衡量性能
But what does good performance mean?
你怎么知道你做完了并且完成的足够出色
How do you know when you're done and when you're good enough?
非常简单
ELISABETH MORANT: Well, that's easy.
一个页面加载的时间
It's just the amount of time it takes a page to load.
页面加载时间
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So page load time
人尽皆知
is something that we've all known about as a community.
我们把称它为PLT或者是其他
We call it PLT or whatever.
我们有很深的理解  也有强有利的工具
We have good understanding, got good tools.
There's whole conferences on it.
这并不是说我们已经很完美了  顺便说
That's not to say we're perfect, by the way.
很多人都不必去亲身体验
There's a lot of us who don't necessarily
我们在这说的这些东西
practice what we preach here.
但是移动领域  也有其他的指标
But on mobile, other metrics matter, too,
比如说滚动性能
like scrolling performance.
为了实现
To have the illusion that the content is sticking
内容就像随着你手指滚动的错觉
to your finger as you scroll, you've
你必须达到60fps
got to hit 60 frames per second consistently.
但是这些指标哪些是
But which of these metrics should we
值得我们关注并且优化的呢
look at and which one should we be optimizing?
答案就是RAIL
So the answer to that is this concept that we call RAIL.
另外一个缩写
ELISABETH MORANT: Great, another acronym.
当然
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Of course.
就是这个
What did you expect?
它是一个概念
So it's basically a conceptual framework
用来感知什么时候发挥出了出色性能
for knowing when you have good enough performance.
那么什么时候才算性能出色呢
So the key insight is when is performance good enough?
就是用户察觉不到性能的问题的时候
Well, when the user can't perceive it.
这才是性能出色
That's when it's good enough.
我感保证Don Draper可没说过那个
ELISABETH MORANT: I'm pretty sure Don Draper didn't actually
say that.
好眼力
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Good catch.
据我所知他的确没说过
He didn't say that, as far as I know,
但是他说过
but he might have said it if only
如果他想关注某个东西的一方面
he had cared about this kind of stuff.
那么就要为此
But the point is there's actually
做出足够的研究
a lot of research on this.
所以如果你想实现所谓的平滑滚动
So if you're trying to get that illusion of smooth motion,
那么一定得达到60fps
of course you want to hit 60 frames per second,
意味着每一帧至少要16.67毫秒
which means 16.67 milliseconds to put each frame on screen.
而现在  如果你想要用户
Now, if you want to have the user feel
感到这一切都是瞬间完成的
that the thing happened instantaneously,
研究告诉我们至少得100毫秒
research tells us you've got about 100 milliseconds.
如果你在一秒内完成
And if you do something within one second, well then,
人的思路能停留在上面
someone's train of thought can stay on it,
如果你超过了十秒
and if you take more than 10 seconds,
那就能玩纸牌了
well then they're off playing solitaire or something.
肯定超过十秒
ELISABETH MORANT: Definitely took more than 10 seconds.
真是一个好例子
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Thank you for that great example.
无论如何这有一个黄金法则需要你去遵守
So anyway, these are the golden standard for you to hit,
而RAIL的概念则是为此而生
and RAIL is basically just hitting
专注于web性能
these goals in the context of your web performance.
第一个R代表响应时间
So the first one is R for reaction time.
这是代表
So basically, this is exactly when
从用户开始滑动屏幕上的手指
the user puts their finger down on the glass
再到开始交互的时间
and starts interacting.
你有100毫秒的时间处理事务
You have 100 milliseconds to do something, to show you got it.
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah, sure.
否则的话应用就会感觉卡顿
Otherwise, the app feels broken or slow.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Exactly.
100毫秒内改变按钮的颜色
So that's 100 milliseconds to change the button color
或者展示一个进度条
or to show a loading indicator or show, I got it.
证明没有卡住
I'm not frozen.
A代表动画时间
Next one is Animation time.
60帧每秒是黄金法则
You've got, of course, 60 frames per second
意味着每帧16.67毫秒
is the gold standard, which means 16.67 milliseconds.
不算太长
Now, that's not a lot of time, so if you do anything,
你可能会错过  所以一定要格外注意
you might miss that, so you have to really, really careful.
I则是代表空闲
So the next one is Idle.
为啥Idle是RAIL的一部分
ELISABETH MORANT: Why is Idle part of RAIL?
你必须得做一些工作
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So you have to do
这要花些时间  比如说渲染图片什么的
some work that's going to take some time, like image decodes
无论如何你不能在用户交互时干这个
or whatever, and you can't do it when the user is interacting,
最佳时间是用户还没把手指
so a good time is when the user doesn't have
放在屏幕上
their finger on the screen.
ELISABETH MORANT: Right.
如果用户在你做这些工作的途中
ALEX KOMOROSKE: However, what if the user's finger comes back
手指放回来了会怎样
in while you're doing that work?
我想想
ELISABETH MORANT: I see.
你一定不想在中途发生这个
You don't want to be the middle of idle time
因为这样的话  你就无法完成交互
because otherwise, you're not going to be able to react.
用户会以为卡住了
The user might think the app is broken.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Right.
所以如果你想确保在没开始与用户交互之前
So you want to make sure you chunk up your work you
也就是Idle阶段
that you even in idle so if at any point
就完成整体的工作
the user starts interacting with you, you're good to go
你最好要抓住那100毫秒的响应时间
and can hit that 100 milliseconds, the R of RAIL.
最后一个  则是加载时间
And the last one, of course, is our friend Load time.
当然  这在移动端仍然是问题
Of course, it still matters, if not more, on mobile.
黄金法则告诉我们
And the gold standard here to keep the train
临界值在1秒
of thought solid is one second.
我希望一切都能载入的那样快
ELISABETH MORANT: I wish everything loaded that fast.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Yeah.
It's pretty low, right?
请记住  这样才算是完美的性能
Remember, this is for perfect performance,
Quick 和 Service Worker 首次让此
and things like Quick and Service Worker
得以可行
actually make this feasible for the first time.
当然  如果你不能全部的都加载出来
And of course, if you can't get your entire site loaded up
还有一个技巧则是
on screen, well, the next best thing
在屏幕展示一些标识来证明我在加载
is putting reasonable pixels on screen to show I've loaded,
我在努力加载  我没有卡住
I'm working, I'm not just stuck.
一些加载进度条什么的
ELISABETH MORANT: Sure, some loading image.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Right.
这就是整个的理论
ELISABETH MORANT: So this is all great in theory,
但是实际中又意味着什么呢
but what does it actually mean in practice?
RAIL对于我们来说
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So RAIL is a great conceptual framework
是一个良好的概念性框架
for us across the community.
尤其是对于浏览器厂商
So for browser vendors in particular,
它给予你如开发者般
it means giving you as developers
更多的上升空间  你亲自去操刀你的代码
more headroom, more space for your own code
完成这些工作  这样你就能跨越这些壁垒
to do this work so that you don't cross those boundaries.
Chrome的Web平台团队
So the Chrome Web Platform team is
就是一路过来的  大约有200个工程师
way over-- I think 200 engineers last time I checked.
很多人  并且绝大多数的人
A lot of people, the vast majority,
都在为性能方面努力着
work on some aspect of performance.
我们为此做了大量的工作  以及大量的重构
We've been doing tons of work, vast re-architectures,
旨在优化移动端的性能
to optimize for mobile performance.
我们没有太多的时间去深说其中的每一个
Now, we don't have time to dive into any of these in any depth,
但是让我选其中的一个
but let me just pick one.
两个月前  我们启动了一个新特性
So a couple months ago, we launched this feature
叫做Scheduler
called the Scheduler.
大意是说
And the basic idea is that when you
当你开始和一个界面开始交互的时候
start interacting with a page, that's when, of course,
滚动优先于一切
you want to prioritize scrolling and frames over everything
else.
这样的效果非常显著
And it turns out that this can have a really big impact,
尤其是在拥有大量资源要加载
especially during page load when there's
以及工作要做的情况下
lots of work being done.
这里有一个演示视频  打开一个视频界面
So here we've got a video, and if you can roll the video,
左边开启了scheduler  而右边则没有开启
we have on the left with the scheduler, on the right
without.
我们刷新一下重新加载界面
We refresh the page so we're doing tons of work,
你可以非常明显的看到
and you can see the one on the left scrolls way
左边比右边的滑动的更顺滑
more smoothly than the one on the right.
这就是一个由RAIL理念驱动的良好例子
So this is a great example of RAIL motivating work for us
浏览器厂商自动使你的网页
as browser vendors to make your site just
变得更快
get faster automatically.
[APPLAUSE]
谢谢
Thanks.
下一张slide
So if we can move on to the next slide.
不仅仅是我们自己
So it's not just on us.
我们也为开发者们
It's also on developers that work with us.
提供了良好的工具
And so part of it is better tooling
这样的话你就能轻易的了解性能情况
so that you can understand your own performance really well.
当然  DevTools是一个无比强大的工具
So of course, DevTools is incredibly powerful.
一个你现在可以在Canary 版本里体验到的新特性
A new feature that you can try out in Canary behind the flag
叫做Filmstrip
today is a feature called Filmstrip.
它是怎样工作的呢  你会注意到
So what it does, it shows you-- you can see it up there
那里有一行图片
in that row of images-- it shows what
它展示出了加载页面时
pixels were on screen at different parts
不同时刻的情况
as you loaded the page.
你可以看到
And so you can see here this random cwilso guy,
加载他的博客大约用了8秒
his blog is hitting about eight seconds for the pixels
才完全的体现在屏幕上
to be on screen, which is way past the one
当你想要用RAIL的理念去优化它
second that you want with RAIL.
这样的话  你就需要通过DevTools深挖
And so now, of course, you dig in with DevTools
看看究竟是怎么回事
and figure out what's going on.
所以说DevTools是一个强大的工具
ELISABETH MORANT: So DevTools is really powerful
当时你需要拥有一个PhD才能弄懂他
but you basically need a PhD to understand all of it.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Yeah.
有时候它的确是压倒性般强大
It's so overwhelmingly powerful sometimes.
我们也在这方面努力
So we're also working on tools that
这样当你打开DevTools
will make it so that you can open up DevTools
它会说hey  你忽略了
and it will say, hey, you're consistently
RAIL规则中的A
missing the A in RAIL.
这个统计功能的第三方脚本
Turns out that this third party script, this analytic script,
妨碍了滚动工作
is doing way too much work on scroll.
你该考虑移走它
Consider removing it.
这样的话就容易多了
And so making it much easier for you to dive in
在你没有拿到PhD的情况下
without having to get a PhD.
最后一个则是
And of course, the last one is just
把我们自己 看成是高标准的
holding ourselves as web developers
web开发者
to a higher standard.
I\O的web应用就是个很好的例子
So the I/O web app is an amazing example
一个高度响应式  能到达60fps的Web应用
of a highly responsive, 60 frames per second web app.
目前这个开发不容易  但是每一天都会变得
Now, it wasn't easy to build but it is getting easier and easier
越来越简单
every day.
对于我们来说
And all of us, every single time we
当我们引入一个第三方的脚本或者是资源
include a third party script or resource
以及从第三方域名上取得的东西
or we fetch out to another third party domain,
我们应该问问自己这样值得吗
we should ask ourselves, is this worth it?
用RAIL理念的话会更快吗
Is this going to make me go past those goals in RAIL?
我们花了不少时间谈论性能
So there's only so much time to cover performance.
旨在说明我们已经做到了巨大的进步
The point is that we've made a lot of big strides
我觉得这对于我们来说是一个良好的理念框架
and I think this is a great framework for us
as a community.
Web有着广阔的延伸范围
ELISABETH MORANT: So the web has a superpower of reach,
我们现在已经达到了60fps  即使是对于一些
and now it's possible to have 60 frames per second, even
非常复杂的移动应用
for the most complex mobile apps,
但是web所缺少的则是
but what the web is missing is the ability
帮助用户和那些他们真正需要的内容
for users to build meaningful relationships with the stuff
构建起联系的能力
that they find to really engage.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Yeah.
速配虽好
So I mean, speed dating is great.
你会在短时间内遇见各式各样的人
You meet a whole bunch of people in a very short amount of time,
但是如果你和你遇到的人
but what if you meet that person and you
都碰不出火花呢
got a little bit of a spark?
你不想深入的了解他们
You want to get to know them a little bit.
的确  本地应用在此做的就比较好
ELISABETH MORANT: Exactly, and native apps are great at this.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
507zuoda
我有个主意
I've got an idea.
我们为什么不把
Why don't we just list all the things
本地应用能做到的移植到Web上面
native apps can do and just copy that for the web?
看着简单
ELISABETH MORANT: Well, I wish it were that easy.
问题是
The problem is that with every new API also
也会带来全新的风险
comes a whole new set of risks, and we
我们要保证Web的安全性
want to maintain the security guarantees
以及不能让用户从一个链接跳转到另一个链接时
of the web, the ability for users to jump to a link
承担相关的风险
and not worry that something's going to happen to them.
举个例子  后台同步
So let's take, for example, background sync, background
后台同步得以在应用关闭的情况下
sync being the ability for an app to fetch and send content
与服务器交换数据
when the app is closed.
如果你每一个月浏览超过100个站点
So if you're visiting over 100 sites a month,
你当然不愿意让它们在后台
then you don't necessarily want them all to arbitrarily start
随意的进行同步
syncing the background.
比如说你在家浏览一些令人尴尬的站点
Just like let's say you browse some embarrassing sites
比如明星八卦绯闻什么的
at home, like some celebrity gossip site.
我当然不是说Alex热衷于
I'm not going to call what celebrity Alex is
明星绯闻哈
obsessed with.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Guilty.
然后你要去工作了
ELISABETH MORANT: And then you go to work,
于此同时你手机没有电了
and in the meantime, your phone lost battery.
当你工作时你打开了它  瞬间
You turn it on when you get to work, and all of a sudden,
后台开始同步那些令人尴尬的信息
you start fetching embarrassing content while you're
在你的企业网络里
on your corporate network.
我们试图拯救那些像Alex一样
Well, we're trying to save people like Alex
从浏览一个尴尬站点再到被叫进主管办公室的那些人
from an embarrassing visit to the sys admin's office.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
我知道了
I get that.
我明白了
I see.
让我们回到刚才的那个速配比喻
ELISABETH MORANT: And so basically, if we bring back
假如说
the speed dating metaphor, let's say
你第一次遇见了一个
that you meet someone for the first time
可以碰撞出火花并且你觉得
and you really feel that spark and you think,
这就是你要找的那一个
this could be the one.
你会给她们你公寓的钥匙吗
Do you give them the keys to your apartment,
或者是带她见家长  半跪着求婚
introduce them to your parents, bend down on one knee
并且发誓要彼此共度余生吗
and vow to spend the rest of your life together?
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Yes.
ELISABETH MORANT: No.
当然不
Of course not.
天啊  那可能会是一个连环杀手
Jeez, that could be a serial killer.
你需要的是慢慢的培养出感情
So the idea is that you want to build a relationship slowly.
问题在于我们无法效仿  或者是把本地应用的强大模型
The problem is that we can't necessarily emulate or copy
复制过来
the powerful model of native apps
因为本地应用有商店  它们有运维团队
because native apps have a store, they have ops teams,
而web则是开放的
and the web is open.
我们想做的
And so what we want to do is enable
只是逐渐的开启Web请求使用
websites to progressively ask permission
更加强大特性的权限
for powerful and engaging features.
应该由用户表明
And the idea is that users should
什么时候他们想信任该站点
be able to indicate when they want
并且给予相关的权限
to trust this site enough to give them certain permissions.
如果每一个人都能访问到你的银行账户
Basically, if everyone got access to your bank account
只要你见到他们的时候
as soon as you met them, you probably
你可能一步都不会离开你的家门
wouldn't want to leave your house.
相比于拥有这些能力
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So it's more important for the reach
为你保留Web的广度
of the web than to have all these capabilities
比此更加的重要
for every random site you go to.
ELISABETH MORANT: Exactly.
明白了
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Got it.
所以说
ELISABETH MORANT: And so the idea
这些新API也会带来全新的风险
is that with all these new APIs come a set of risks,
Chrome有这个责任来确保
and Chrome has this responsibility
每一个用户浏览的网页都是安全的
to make sure that people can still browse the web securely.
从这个角度说
Now, with this in mind, we've already
我们已经把部分API带到了Web上
brought a few exciting APIs to the web
我们今天谈谈其中的两个
and we're going to talk about two of them right now.
第一个是添加到主屏幕
The first is Add to Homescreen.
打字  尤其是在移动端上
So typing, especially on a mobile,
是非常困难的  但是移动端也是人们消磨时间最多的地方
is really hard, but mobile is where people go to kill time.
当你到咖啡厅去
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So, I mean, you go to the coffee shop
和你朋友见面的时候
to meet your friend.
他们还没到
They aren't there yet.
你想读一些有趣的东西
You want to read something interesting but not
但是又很无趣因为随时他们都可能会出现
too interesting because at any point they might show up
你必须把你的手机放在一边
and you have to put your phone away.
ELISABETH MORANT: Exactly.
你可以打开你的手机  点击一个图标
So you open up your phone, you tap an icon,
然后你沉浸其中
and you fall into some experience
你随时都可以退回来
that you're OK jumping back out of again.
我们早已为用户推出了这个
And so we already have the ability for people
添加站点到主屏幕的特性
to add sites to their home screen.
它在设置里的层级很深
It's buried deep in the settings,
但是我们发现它却有着超高的使用率
but we found it had surprisingly high usage.
我们为什么不能弄得更加明显些
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So why don't we just make that way more obvious
这样就不容易被忽略了
and make it really hard to miss?
ELISABETH MORANT: Well, if people
如果人们每月访问100个网站的话
are visiting 100 websites every month,
并不是每个都是有用的
then probably every new help form you go to,
你不必都想把它填到主屏幕上
you don't want to necessarily add it to your home screen.
我们的做法是利用一些真正智能启发性机制
And so what we've done is we've incorporated some really smart
开发者可以使用这个API
heuristics and said developers can use this API
让应用请求被添加到主屏上面
and request to be added to the home screen
只要用户和应用有着足够充分的接触
as long as people have in each with the app enough
我们就能检测到用户的确是想把那个应用
that we've detected that they actually want
添加到主屏幕上
that app on their home screen.
我举个例子
So take this as an example.
我非常喜欢阅读Vice News
I really enjoy reading Vice News,
这周的早些时候我阅读了一篇文章
and I read an article earlier this week.
并且早上我又打开了
And this morning I opened it up again,
我发现收到了是否把Vice News
And I found that I got this prompt from Vice to add
添加到主屏幕上的请求
the website to my home screen.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
非常酷  但是要是你在没联网的情况下
That's awesome, but what happens if you tap that
打开它会怎样
and you don't have connectivity?
你肯定不想看到的是
ELISABETH MORANT: Well, what you don't
那个可怕的离线小恐龙
want to see is the dreaded offline dinosaur,
然而本地应用在这方面处理的就非常的好
and so native apps actually handle this case very well.
即使是一个只有网络连接才能工作的应用
Even if an app depends on connectivity to work,
它们通常会有一个屏幕界面说
they usually have some sort of splash screen saying,
sorry 你还不能使用这个  稍后回来
sorry, you can't use this, but come back later,
等等对应用一些的自定义
something custom to the app.
出于这个原因  我们只对
And for that reason, we've only enabled
那些拥有良好离线体验的站点
Add to Homescreen for those sites that
开启了添加到主屏幕的功能
have a meaningful offline experience.
所以说
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Which is a great point
离线体验格外重要
that offline is an incredibly important thing
尤其是对于在移动网络上创造出色体验来说
for building engaging experiences on mobile web.
在你的移动设备上
So obviously, on your mobile devices,
你更可能出现连接不稳定或者是无连接的情况
you're way more likely to have a flaky connectivity
比如参加了Wi-Fi坏掉了的
or no connectivity, like being at a tech conference where
一个技术会议
the Wi-Fi doesn't work exactly as it should.
这也是一个历史性问题
The problem is that historically, we've only
我们只能通过应用缓存来解决
had App Cache to handle this.
应用缓存有什么问题吗
ELISABETH MORANT: So what's the problem with App Cache?
应用缓存还不是那么的流行
ALEX KOMOROSKE: App Cache wasn't exactly very popular.
非常容易上手  很好
So it was easy to get started, which is great,
and it's declarative, which is also great,
但是却有几分复杂
but it's kind of complex.
如果你做的事情比较复杂
If you do anything rather slightly complex,
你就不能做你想做的事情
you can't do the things you want to do
并且很快就失败了
and it quickly falls down.
在实际中它并不适用
It is unworkable in practice.
所以你需要的是更多的掌控
So what you need, of course, is more control,
而Service Worker可以帮你掌控
and Service Worker brings you that control.
让我讲讲它是如何工作的
So let me tell you how it works.
大意是说当你访问一个站点
The basic idea is when you visit a site,
你可以安装一个Service Worker
you can install a Service Worker,
Service Worker 是一个基本的
and that Service Worker is basically
脚本
a script off to the side.
当浏览器准备从域名上
And now, when the browser is going
获取资源的时候
to fetch a resource from your domain,
不是直接的去访问网络
instead of going to the network, it
而是去问Service Worker   hey  你想要做什么
asks the Service Worker, hey, what do you want to do?
Service Worker会说
And the Service Worker can say, just do
做你要做的吧  请去访问网络
what you would have done, go to the network, please,
或者是说请到缓存里面去取
or it can say, please hand back this thing from the cache,
甚至是忽略这个请求
or it can even say, create a resource on the fly
并返回
and pass that.
所以说  这是一个
ELISABETH MORANT: So basically, it's
用JavaScript写的代理客户端
a client side proxy written in JavaScript.
差不多
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Exactly.
这个能让你更加任意地构建出复杂的
So this allows you to build arbitrarily
离线体验
complex offline experiences.
当我说任意地的时候
And when I say &quot;arbitrarily,&quot; what I mean is you
我是指你可以构建出及其复杂或者是十分简单的例子
can build something extremely complex or extremely simple.
I/O的web应用就是一个很好的
So the I/O web app is a great example
复杂的离线web应用
of a complex offline web app.
它能够准确的进行缓存  即使你是在
It does very careful caching so that even if you load it
完全离线的情况下  你也能获得出色的体验
when you're fully offline, you get something meaningful,
但是当你连接上了网络  它会为你展现一个用户界面
but then when you're connected, it will show you UI about, hey,
这有新的内容
there's fresh content.
点开看看吧
Tap here to see it.
当然  更像一个解决方案
Of course, a more likely scenario or easier scenario
一个简单的能缓存一切的解决方案
is just to aggressively cache everything
你可以使用它这样就可以进行离线工作了
you use so that your thing works offline.
这有一个叫做sw-precache的Gulp插件
There's a great Gulp plug-in called sw-precache
它能够很容易的帮你这个集成到你的工作流里面
that makes it incredibly easy to integrate into your workflows.
当然  这样的话
And of course, the simplest possible thing you can do
你就能摆脱那个可怕的离线小恐龙
is get rid of that darn offline dinosaur for your thing
并且和Service Worker说hello了
and basically say, hey Service Worker,
当用户离线来访问我的站点时
if the user tries to fetch my site and we're fully offline,
看到的不是离线小恐龙
instead of showing the offline dinosaur,
而是我事先准备好的界面
just show my own little splash screen
说  请连接网络后再试
that says, please connect to the internet and try again.
这个几行JavaScript 代码就搞定了
That takes only a few lines of JavaScript.
Service Worker 处理离线来说实在是酷极了
So Service Worker is cool for offline,
但是它还有一个绝招
but it has another trick up its sleeve.
一个Service Worker可以和多个标签页进行通讯
So a Service Worker, a single one, can talk to multiple tabs
它也可以不和任何标签页通讯
or it can talk to no tabs.
这也是第一个地方  开发者可以编写和运行脚本
So it's the first place that we as developers have a place
即使是没有任何一个站点标签页在运行
to write and run script even when no tabs for my site
are open.
这很糟
ELISABETH MORANT: That's bad.
用户不希望有任何一个脚本
People don't want any random site executing
在后台执行
scripts in the background.
的确  但是这也是为什么Service Worker
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Exactly, and that's
是事件驱动的
why Service Workers are event driven.
那么当访问网络的事件开始时  都发生了什么了呢
So what happens is a networking event happens, the browser goes
浏览器会到Service Worke那 说
to the Service Worker and says, hey,
Hey 我监测到了一个网络事件
I've got this network event.
Service worker就开始处理并完成它
Service worker handles it and then it's done.
它仅仅就是呆在那里不做任何事
It's just sitting there not doing anything because it
因为它也不能做
can't.
其余的时间我们则把它冻结
And so at that point, we can freeze dry that thing,
并放进存储里
put it off in storage.
直到浏览器发送新的事件
ELISABETH MORANT: Right, until the browser sends a new event
才把它唤醒
to wake it up.
对的
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Exactly.
当一个新事件过来时
So when a new event comes in, we bring it
我们把它快速的放入内存  非常的快
back into memory really quickly, which takes,
我觉得大约只需50毫秒  将其投入工作
I think, around 50 milliseconds or so in practice in the wild,
这样它就能做自己的事
and then it can go on its way.
还有就是Service Worker
So the cool thing is that this isn't just related
不只是和网络事件相关
to network events.
你可以想象它与其它的事件配合
You can also imagine other types of events
将其唤醒并工作
that would potentially wake it up to do work.
我懂了
ELISABETH MORANT: I see.
所以浏览器可以基于用户的实际需求
So the browser can choose what type of event
去选择它想要发送的请求
it wants to send based on what it thinks the user actually
wants.
就是这样
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Exactly.
这非常的强大
So this is really powerful.
它带给了web
It enables an entirely new class of functionality
一个之前不可能做到的新功能
that before wasn't even possible to bring to the web.
还有带来了另一个新特性
ELISABETH MORANT: So one of the new features only made
Service worker 可以推送通知
possible because of Service Worker is push notifications.
直到现在  只有本地应用才可以
Until now, only native apps were able to send
推送通知
push notifications, but there are
但是仍然会有很多情况你想推送通知
cases where you would want push without everything else that
comes with being an app.
这很重要吗
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So are these important?
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah.
这非常重要
This is extremely important.
通知领域是一个新的战场
Basically, notifications are game changing for engagement.
当人们和手机交互的时候
More and more, people are interacting with their phone,
打开新的应用并且开始体验
opening up new apps and experiences largely
是因为他们事先收到了通知
because they got a notification first,
而这种情况越来越不常见  那就是
and it's much less common that people will open up their phone
人们打开手机查看应用列表
and dumbly look at their app grid
来决定他们该用那一个应用
and decide what they want to use.
这有一个例子
Here's an example.
卫报有一个本地应用
So the Guardian has a native app and they
并且他们发现当重大事件发生后的几个小时后
found that in the hours after a breaking news event, up to 40%
从收到推送通知而过来的文章阅读量上升到40%
of their article views came from push notifications alone.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wow.
非常巨大
ELISABETH MORANT: It's huge.
我来展示一下通知的重要性
And so to demonstrate how important this is,
我将进行一个demo
I'm going to jump into a demo.
9个月前的奥斯卡季  我在家里
So nine months ago, Oscars season, I was at home
但是我有一大堆的工作要做
but I had to do a lot of work so I
所以就不能去看奥斯卡颁奖礼的直播
wasn't able to watch the Academy Awards live.
这对我来说很不爽
This was a huge bummer for me, so what I ended up doing was
所以我停下了手头的工作
I would jump between my computer and then I
一直在刷新卫报的直播博客看看谁获奖了
kept refreshing the Guardian live blog to see who had won.
我不断的刷屏
And what I would do is I'd refresh
我想看看Reese Witherspoo穿什么了
and I'd see what Reese Witherspoon is wearing,
并且不断的点击
and then I'd click on that and look
看看她过去的电影海报  然后心神不宁的
at some of her past filmography, and then just get distracted
回到电脑上继续工作
and jump back to my computer.
其实啥事都没做
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Basically, getting nothing done.
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah.
什么工作都没做
Basically, I was not getting anything done, or at least
一份任务也没完成
I wasn't getting a lot of work done.
但是如果卫报可以推送消息的话会怎样
But what if the Guardian had push notifications?
要是我不用这样折腾来折腾去
What if I didn't have to jump in and engage
卫报就可以告诉我那些
and instead the Guardian told me when there was information
我想知道的信息
that I actually wanted to know.
我开始打开直播博客向下滚动
So suppose I open up the live blog and I scroll down
我看到了开启通知的按钮
and I see the ability to follow the story.
卫报说明了为什么我该选择打开通知
So the Guardian explains why I'd want
因为我想及时的获取
to opt in to notifications, I want
这个内容的信息
to engage with this particular piece of content,
所以我选择了开启浏览器通知
so I hit Enable Browser Notifications.
与此同时Chrome询问我
And at this point, Chrome sends me the prompt,
要不要打开通知  我选择了接受
and yes, I want notifications, so I say Allow.
Great.
所以现在的话我就可以接收到
So, now confident that I'm going to get notifications
我感兴趣的内容的通知了
about the content I'm interested in,
我关闭了Chrome继续去工作
I can just close Chrome and get back to work.
我在工作并且收到了一个通知
So I'm working and I see a notification.
我不知道你们能不能看到它
I don't know if you can see it.
我从未测试过这个
I haven't tested this out.
我在手表上收到了这个通知
So I see a notification on my watch
它说最佳音效剪辑奖揭晓了
that says that sound editing won some award.
这是一个我不感冒的奖项所以我清除通知了
Now, this is one of those lame awards so I just swipe it away.
我不感兴趣
I don't care.
所以你在手表上收到了通知
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So you got that on your watch?
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah.
我在手表上收到了通知
I got it on my watch because Chrome sends notifications
是因为Chrome会像其他Android一样发送通知
just like any other Android app would, and in that same way,
我在手机上收到通知
I get notifications on my phone just like I
就像其他的消息应用一样
do from my messaging apps.
我对刚才的内容不感兴趣继续回去工作
So I wasn't interested in that content, so I go back to work,
喝咖啡  吃甜甜圈  写重要的摘要
drinking coffee, eating donuts, writing very important briefs.
Oh.
我收到了另外一个通知
I see another notification.
它说鸟人获得了最佳影片奖
And this one, of course, &quot;Birdman&quot; won best picture.
我们都觉得布达佩斯大饭店
I mean, clearly we all know that the movie that should have
应该拿到这个奖
won the award was &quot;The Grand--&quot;
等等
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Wait, wait.
布达佩斯大饭店
ELISABETH MORANT: &quot;The Grand Budapest Hotel,&quot;
我想在座的各位都会同意我的看法
which I'm sure everyone else in the room agrees with me about.
为了表达我的看法
So in order to express my opinion,
我会查看通知打开直播的网页
maybe I'll dive into the live blog, open up the website,
也许会写一些有品位的评论
maybe leave a few very tastefully written comments
关于为什么这部电影该获奖
about why this movie should have won.
我不耽误大家时间了
Anyway, but I won't bore you with that now.
通知推送的重要之处
So the point is push notifications
在于让你获取到你想要的信息
let you know information when you want it.
Alex?
怎么了
ALEX KOMOROSKE: What?
非常抱歉
ELISABETH MORANT: I'm so sorry.
你要知道这对我来说有多么的重要
Can you just-- you know how to wrap this up.
Imagine Dragons的票已经开卖了
I just-- Imagine Dragons tickets just went on sale.
你在逗我吗
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Are you kidding me?
我们这可是在进行I/O talk
We're in an I/O talk.
我知道  但是我非常喜欢这支乐队
ELISABETH MORANT: I know, but I told you
他们的票马上就要卖光了
they're going to sell out and I really love this band,
我只需要两秒钟  两秒钟
and I just-- it'll take me, like, two seconds.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
Great.
我想我们该回到刚才的那页slide
I guess why don't we go back to the slides?
我觉得 Elisabeth是说
So I think the point that Elisabeth was going to make
通知推送的重要性
is that push notifications are great.
在某种情况下  通知即是内容
In some cases, the notification is the content.
一看便知
You get all you need just by seeing it.
或许你也想打开里面进去看
In some cases, you want to dive in.
有些时候
And in other cases, it's information
某些通知对你来说十分重要
that is so important to you that you want it to interrupt you
你想在任何时候任何地点都能收到它
at any time or place, including when you're presenting in front
即使是站在百人之前的I/O演讲上面
of hundreds of people at I/O.
我买到票啦
ELISABETH MORANT: I got the tickets.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Great.
祝贺
So happy for you.
希望这挺值
Hope it was worth it.
无论如何
ELISABETH MORANT: Anyway, the point
通知推送的关键之处在于这是一个新的主动交互方式
is that push notifications are this new primary interaction
paradigm.
也是人们与应用融洽沟通的方式
It's how people engage with their apps.
把通知推送带到web上来
And bringing push notifications to the web
得以让你真正能够关注你想关注的东西
allows you get information about what you care about
before you've decided to necessarily commit
to everything else that comes with an app.
举个例子  我每个月都要访问Ticketmaster一次
So for example, I visit Ticketmaster once every couple
我非常希望能收到
of months, but I really wanted notifications
关于这部分内容的通知
about this particular piece of content.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
那么我们什么时候
So the obvious question that we all have
可以用上这个
is when can we use this?
六个月之后
Six months from now?
一年之后
A year from now?
就是现在  对所有的Chrome用户开放
ELISABETH MORANT: Well, this is shipped to all Chrome users
任何人访问一个具有开启了启用通知的站点
today, so anyone who visits a site with this enabled
都能够接收到通知推送
will be able to get push notifications or the Add
或者是添加到主屏幕
to Homescreen prompt and developers
开发者也可以添加这个新功能到他们的站点
can start adding this to their site at any time.
And so the Guard--
[APPLAUSE]
我觉得这是一个很好的工具
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I think it's pretty cool, too.
非常酷
ELISABETH MORANT: Pretty cool, right?
卫报和票务大师的工程师团队
So the Guardian and Ticketmaster,
制作出了你今天所看到的演示原型
both of these engineering teams built the prototypes
并且他们打算
that you saw today, and they're planning
在未来的几个月内在他们的站点
on bringing push notifications to their sites
推出通知推送的新功能
live in the coming months.
不仅仅是他们
And they're not the only ones.
我们有一些合作商
We have a number of early adopters
也将会在接下来的几周内推出这个功能
who are rolling out push notifications within the coming
weeks.
真是非常酷炫的东西
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So the cool thing about this, too,
这个只能在Chrome上面用吗
is this isn't just some Chrome only feature.
我们也和Mozilla进行了合作
We designed this very collaboratively with Mozilla,
在相关的规范上也同样适用
working in standards bodies.
事实上这是一张来自Firefox的截图
And in fact, this is a screenshot from Firefox
几天之前截的  Firfox的Night版本弹出相关信息
that I took a couple days ago, Nightly Build with a flag
咨询用户获取通知推送的权限
flipped that shows them asking for permission
for push notifications.
这也是一个非常好的例子
So that will be coming there at some point, too.
激动人心
It's pretty exciting.
Service Worker 为我们带来了新的功能
So Service Workers allows us to bring all kinds of capabilities
得以让那些以前不能实现的事情实现
to the web that before really didn't make sense
or couldn't make sense.
我们也和其他的浏览器厂商合作
And because we're designing them with other browser vendors
制定出相关规范
and standards bodies, it's something
得以让你在不同的平台上使用
that you can come to rely on.
它仿佛开创了移动互联网的一个新纪元
It's kind of like the dawn of a new era for the mobile web.
ELISABETH MORANT: OK.
我们今天只关注当下  不讨论未来
We promised we were only going to talk about today, not
the future.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: OK.
另外的一个好消息是
Well, the cool thing about this is
你今天就可以使用它  并且这些新特性
you can start today because these features are
都是渐进增强的
great at progressive enhancement.
所以当你通过浏览器
So if you go to one of these sites in a browser that doesn't
去一个不支持通知推送的站点
support push notifications, well, you see the same site
你会发现它和之前没什么两样
that you would have seen before, but if you
但是当你去一个支持通知推送的站点
go to that site in a browser that does support push
也许他们会在那里添加一个按钮
notifications, maybe they add another button that says,
hey 当内容发生变化的时候通知我
hey, I want to be notified when this thing changes.
假如我是用户并选择的话  选择后者
And then if I as a user opt in, I
因为我有更高价值的事情
can have a really high value thing
对我来说更加的重要
that's really important to me even before it's
在这个特性在被每一个浏览器支持之前
shipped in every browser out there,
所以我觉得这非常激动人心
so I think that's pretty exciting.
我们今天讨论了
ELISABETH MORANT: So we talked about a lot
大量高层面的话题
of topics at a high level today, but there
但是仍然有很多高质量的DevByte以及Box Talk
are a number of DevBytes and box talks
你可以参加  以便做更加深入的了解
that you can visit that will go into a lot of these topics
more in depth.
我们今天讨论了三件事
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So today, we talked about three things.
web的强大力量以及它的范围
ELISABETH MORANT: The superpower of the web, reach.
移动互联网上面做出的巨大性能进步
ALEX KOMOROSKE: How performance has made huge strides
on mobile web.
以及我们创造出强大的新方式
ELISABETH MORANT: And how we're baking powerful new ways
帮助用户和那些他们真正需要的内容建立起联系
for you to build relationships with your users, many available
它们有的现在可用或者即将到来
now and a lot more coming soon.
把这三方面孤立起来看
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So the three of these
没有什么特别
alone aren't that special.
但是把它们联合在一起来看
It's the confluence of these three things
就变得非常重要
that's really important.
你忘记了最重要的一点
ELISABETH MORANT: Well, you're forgetting the most important
one.
正是这些
ALEX KOMOROSKE: That's a good point because these things
才让创造伟大的东西成为可能
by themselves, they just make it possible to do cool things,
但是当你把它
but what happens when you combine
和全球化阵营的能工巧将们联系在一起的时候
that with this global community of tinkerers and builders
这将创造出无比强大并且令人振奋的作品
and makers, well, that's when something really awe inspiring
happens.
我都有些迫不及待了想看看你构建的作品了
ELISABETH MORANT: We can't wait to see what you build.
谢谢
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Thanks.
[APPLAUSE]
大家有什么问题
So I think if there are any live questions,
可以现场提问
we can take them here.
首先  非常精彩的演讲
AUDIENCE: First of all, fantastic talk.
谢谢
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Thank you.
问题是关于Service Worker
AUDIENCE: The question is about the Service Workers
响应事件的
which respond to events.
它会包含类似于Ajax请求
Does it involve events like Ajax requests
或者是网络无法正常连接的事件吗
or it's only when you don't have a network which in reachless?
当你检测到一个事件时会发生什么
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So basically, what happens
is you get a fetch event.
在你的Service Worker里你会说
So in your Service Worker you say,
Chrome  请在从我域名上获取任何内容时通知我
Chrome, please notify me when any content from my domain
然后你就会捕捉到那个事件
is fetched, and then you'll catch that event,
你会知道请求的URL是什么
you'll pass in what the request URL was, and you
并且你可以为此做出回应
can respond to it that way.
这个在网络连接正常
That happens even when you're fully
以及糟糕的网络连接上都会发生
connected because of course, you might be on flaky connectivity,
所以你要确保已经为你的站点
and so you want to make sure you can design your experience
设计了不同网络环境下
with total control over what happens
良好的体验方式
over networking to your site.
你的意思是像HTML的内容层
AUDIENCE: So you meant content, like HTML,
或者说它包含了Ajax请求的事件
or it includes Ajax requests?
事实上每一个到你站点的请求
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Basically almost every request that
goes to your site.
只有个别是特别
There's a few exceptions for specific things.
如果你使用类似于
AUDIENCE: So if you're using things
OAuth  自动验证的东西
like OAuth, which automatically authenticates,
获取数据的模式是怎样设计的
what's the design pattern to get data?
比如说如果你使用Google plus认证
Like, for example, if you used Google+ authentication,
就会直接在你的页面上登录
which directly logs onto your page--
这觉得是一个好问题
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I think that's a great question
你可以去那边继续的深入讨论
to go into in more depth in the office hours,
但是你已经掌控了一切
but you have total control over this.
这非常之强大
It's pretty powerful.
我想这对你来说是一个简单的问题
AUDIENCE: I've got an easy one for you, I hope.
关于主屏幕
The home screen.
你刚才提到你们能发现有多少用户使用添加到主屏幕的
You mentioned that you find it interesting how many people
use the home screen.
我对此十分震惊
I'm shocked at that.
我在哪里才能看到这个数据  有多少人使用了
Where can I see the numbers for it, how many people actually
添加到主屏幕
add stuff to the home screen?
我不清楚如果我们今天
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So I don't know if we
分享了这些数据会怎样
have those numbers to share today,
我想说的是
but it's one of those things that even
尽管是一个被埋没的特性
despite being a buried feature, I think
我想用户也能在其中发现大量价值
people find a lot of value in.
这也是为什么
That's one of the reasons that we
我们决定通过主动的方式
decided to bring this feature to other websites
把这个特性带到网站上来的原因
in a more proactive way when we feel
在我们确信用户会对此感兴趣的情况下
pretty confident that the user will be interested in that one.
我在哪里可以找到这些数据
AUDIENCE: Where can I find those numbers?
你们是从哪里获得的
Where do you find them from?
非常抱歉
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I'm sorry.
这些都是我们的内部数据
Those are numbers that we have internally.
保密数据
AUDIENCE: Oh, secret numbers.
是的  保密数据
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Yeah, secret numbers.
使用Service Worker的优点是什么
AUDIENCE: What's the advantage of using a Service
比如说在两三年前的愤怒的小鸟上
Worker over something like what we had at Angry
使用 Service Worker
Birds two or three years ago.
在两三年前的Google I/O
At Google I/O two or three years ago,
愤怒的小鸟还在使用着离线存储
they were using offline storage for Angry Birds.
那么使用Service Worker的优点是什么
What's the advantage of using Service Worker?
Service Worker可以
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So Service Worker
帮你细腻的掌控网络上发生的
allows you to have very fine grained control
所有情况
over all aspects of what's happening on the network,
然后你可以使用一些技术类似于 Index DB
so then you can use technologies like Index DB and Explicit
以及 Explicit Cache API
Cache API to do stuff, whereas before, you
然而以前你则被局限在高级别上的声明方法上面
were limited to a very high level declarative approach.
如果它对你适用  这非常好
If it worked for you, it was great, but more likely
但是它也可能对你无用
it didn't work for you.
在一些你想处理的特殊场合
It couldn't do exactly what you wanted
它是无法做到的
to handle in this particular case
所以说它可能对你无用
and so it was basically useless.
Service Work是这样的一种思考方式
So Service Worker, the way to think of it
你熟悉可扩展Web宣言吗
is-- are you familiar with the Extensible Web Manifesto?
这是一个概念
So that's a notion that we should
定义了一些低级的基本类型
be defining the lower level primitives that
解释web平台是如何工作的
explain how the web platform works,
摆脱高级层面上的东西
so getting rid of the high level magic
给开发者接入低级基本类型的权限
and giving developers access to the low level primitives that
让其得以工作
make that magic work.
所以说更像是在App Cache中深挖
So Service Worker is like digging
来弄明白里面都有些什么
down deep below App Cache to figure out what was there
如何工作的并把它传递给开发者
and how it worked and expose that to developers.
你明白吗
Does that make sense?
也许没有  下一个
Probably not, but OK.
Sorry.
我有一个关于在离线状态下
AUDIENCE: I have a question on the user
用户体验的问题
experience on the offline sites that you showed me.
假如用户通过隧道浏览
So let's say the user is traveling inside a tunnel
然后网络中断了
and then there is a network break.
那么我们怎么判断此时这个用户是处于在线
So how do we notify the user at this moment, you are online,
还是离线呢
and then you go offline.
你刚才讲的是离线的情况
This experience that you're having is the offline period,
然后此时网络又回归正常
and then the network can come back again
你再次上线
and you can come online again.
非常好
ALEX KOMOROSKE: That's great.
Service Worker可以
So the cool thing about Service Worker
让你全力掌控你的应用
is you have full control to do what's right for your app.
举个例子
So in particular-- for example, I
我觉得I/O应用实现了这个  当你网络情况很差的时候
think the I/O app does this-- if you're on flaky connectivity,
它会提示  我将会展示默认的从缓存中获取到的内容
it can say, I'm just going to default and show everything
然后去获取新的资源
directly from the cache and then fetch fresh resources.
当用户在浏览的时候
And so what might happen is the user is already looking at it.
新的内容已经获取到了
Fresh content has come back.
你肯定不想
You don't want to go [MAKES NOISE]
就把内容粘贴出来因为这会让用户
and put the content there because they'll
跟不上思路
lose their train of thought.
但是在这些使用Service Worker的demo中
But with Service Worker in some of these demos, what people do
将会有一个很小的UI提示说
is they'll have a small bit of UI that says,
请上拉刷新获取新的内容
&quot;Fresh content is available if you scroll up.&quot;
这样的话  就会连贯起来
And that way, you don't lose your way in the app.
关键在于
But the point is, of course, that you
你可以掌控你应用的一切
have control to do what's right for your app, which
这非常的棒
is pretty exciting.
很棒
AUDIENCE: That's cool.
谢谢
Thank you.
AUDIENCE: Hi.
我的问题是关于你演示的那个demo
My question is in the demo that you showed.
我收到了来自卫报应用的推送通知
I get a notification from the Guardian app
然后你打开卫报的应用图标
and you go to the home screen of the Guardian app icon,
点击打开  并且开始阅读
and then you click, and then you open, and then you read.
能不能直接的点开通知
Is it possible that from the notification directly, I can--
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah.
这仅仅是一个demo中的bug
That was just a bug in the demo.
那么当你点击通知时会发生什么呢
ALEX KOMOROSKE: So what happens is
当你点开通知
when you tap on the notification,
Service Worker会收到事件请求
your Service Worker receives an event
说通知已经被点击
that says the notification was clicked.
此时你可以不做任何处理
At that point, you can say, OK, do nothing,
你也可以保持原来的标签页
or you can say, focus a tab that existed before
或者是打开新标签页
or open a new tab.
ELISABETH MORANT: Yeah.
我希望点击通知
So I was supposed to click on the notification
就直接跳转到我想要了解的通知中的内容上面
and jump directly to the content that it was notifying me about.
AUDIENCE: OK.
谢谢
Thank you.
AUDIENCE: Hi.
非常相似的问题
Very similar question, but rather
但不是关于点击通知
than tapping on a notification, what if you
如果你收到了email链接会怎样
get an email with a link?
会打开什么与之相关联的应用吗
Is there any kind of association that would open up
that installed web app?
我不清楚它具体是怎样工作的
ALEX KOMOROSKE: I don't know the particulars of exactly how it
但是如果你安装了一个
works, but if you are an installed web
带有清单文件的web应用  会出现一些与目标系统
app with a manifest, there will be some cases that
比如Android   不能完美契合的情况
don't necessarily fit exactly perfectly into the intent
我们也一直在这方面努力
system of Android, but we're working on those.
我没有这方面的具体信息
I don't have all the information for you in depth on that,
所以
though.
你可以去那边深入的进行讨论
You should take it to office hours.
好的
AUDIENCE: Sure.
最后一个问题
ALEX KOMOROSKE: One question.
通知设置的同步
AUDIENCE: Are the notification preferences
是通过用户账户还是通过设备来同步的
synced across a user's account or is it per device?
通过设备
ELISABETH MORANT: It's per device.
这样做的原因
ALEX KOMOROSKE: And the reason for that
是不同的设备有着特别的使用背景
is the context that you opt in is very device specific.
所以我个人可能对八卦绯闻感兴趣
So I might be interested in seeing celebrity gossip
因为有这个需求
on my personal-- because I have a thing for that,
很显然  要在我本人的机器上
apparently-- on my personal machine,
但是我并不介意
but I don't care about it enough to be
在我离开时通知我
notified when I'm on the go.
用户的使用背景
And so exactly where the right user context
取决于你所使用的设备  所以它不会被同步
depends on the device you're in, and so it's not synced.
通知设置是针对
AUDIENCE: And is the notification preference
域名或者是特定的网站吗
per domain or per specific website?
主要是域名
ALEX KOMOROSKE: It's per domain, basically.
问题在于  对于站点的作者来说一定要确保
And so the idea is you want to make sure as a site author
非常小心的使用它
that you use it very respectfully.
我们没有在这个通知中
So one thing we didn't show in this
演示的东西是
is the notifications that show up
这里有一个明显的站点设置按钮
have a very obvious Site Settings button
如果用户点击他它  它就会直接的
and if a user taps on that, they're taken directly
跳转到Chrome中那个域名的相关设置
into Chrome Settings for that domain, where
可以通过一系列的操作
it's a couple more taps to revoke permissions
撤销那个域名的相关权限
for that domain.
作为站点的作者
And so as a site author, you want
你必须要确保你向用户们表明了你的权限
to make sure that you explain to users what you're going to do
尊重他们的顾虑
and that you respect their attention because it's
因为对用户来说
very, very easy for them-- of course,
他们非常容易就能撤销你的权限
they're in control-- to revoke permission very easily
如果你违背它的话
if you abuse it.
谢谢
AUDIENCE: Thank you.
ALEX KOMOROSKE: Sure.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
感谢大家
Appreciate it.
[APPLAUSE]